MELVRICK GOH

YISHUN RING ROAD BLK 367, #07-1532, SINGAPORE 760367 | (+65) 9683 1930 | melvrickgoh.2011@sis.smu.edu.sg

Objective

Pursuing an experience where I will be able to utilize my development experiences and people skills, to not only allow grow personally and professionally, but contribute to the needs and service of your company, as well as enhancing my proficiency in developing savvy applications.

Education

Singapore Management University

Singapore

Candidate for Bachelor of Science (Information Systems Management)

Aug 2011 – Present

- GPA : 3.7 (Magna cum Laude | High Distinction)

Honours
Specialized Track
Dean's List 2012 | SIS Scholar
Business Intelligence & Analytics

Expected Completion of Degree : Aug 2015

Anderson Junior College

Singapore

GCE Advanced Level, A-Level Jan 2007 – Dec 2008

Ang Mo Kio Secondary School

Singapore

GCE Ordinary Level, O-Level, 7 Distinctions

Jan 2003 – Dec 2006

Work Experience

DBS Singapore

Singapore

Project Management & Data Analytics Intern

May 2013 - Aug 2013

- DBS Institutional Banking Group, Chief Operating Officer's Governance & Controls Group. Anti-Money Laundering (AML) & Counter Financing of Terrorism (CFT) Unit.
- Configured SharePoint 2010 for 3 different Project Teams for group administration. Designed on the platform an e-Library & Broadcast function for use between local and overseas teams
- Developed application for automated browser testing of vendor developed KYC Enterprise System (Accounts Operating System)
 - o Use of Apache POI, Selenium, Sikuli, JUnit
- Developed exploratory model for client risk profiling using visual analytics and relationship metrics for measuring client commonalities as a way to identify incoming fraudulent behaviour
 - o Use of D3Js, PostGreSql in developing visualizations and managing huge datasets

Singapore Management University

Singapore

Teaching Assistant

Aug 2012 – Present

- Courses: IS201 (Object Oriented Application Development), IS200 (Software Foundations) and SL110 (Fundamentals of Java)
- Responsible for identifying areas of improvement and analysing student learning profile
- Conduct consultation sessions, where relevant for students and assist with their progress follow-up
- Conduct supplementary classes reviewing past coursework and tests for about 50 students per session
- Involved in a student mentorship programme catered to the less adept students and assisted them in making it through the course learning

Immigration and Checkpoints Authority

Singapore

Administrative Executive Mar 2011 – Jul 2011

- Office of citizenship processing. Assisted in reviewing and processing citizenship applications
- Helped manage the informing of applicants on the requirements and process flow of application

Institute of Bioengineering and Nanotechnology

Singapore

Research Assistant

Nov 2008 - Dec 2008

- Researched on a project entitled "Synthesis & Characterization of Polyelectrolyte Complex Fibers"; The study of accelerated regeneration of cell tissue
- Represented IBN at the A*Star internship closing ceremony within Biopolis
- Learnt about the patience and technical rigor required to conduct studies in a secure environment for utmost accuracy

<u>Leadership and Community Service Experience</u>

SMU Information Systems Society

Singapore

Creative Director (9th *Management Committee*)

Jan 2013 – Present

- Leader of a Publications team for the school magazine (PRISM) and acted as liaison for the different stakeholder groups for the development of publication material
- Project Director for maintenance and development of the SISS portal. In charge of a Web Solutions team of student application developers
- Developed OpenPortal (<u>siss.sg/openportal.php</u>), a platform for learning materials for the different undergraduate modules. Produced and curated different lesson summaries for publishing online
- Creative Director for the SIS 10th Anniversary Gala. In charge of the Drunken Coding segment involving the student and faculty instructor competitors. Set the questions and developed a high-volume capable voting application (siss.meteor.com/) for an audience of 600 to influence competitors' progress during fun mode. (Built using Meteor.js, a Node.js variant with Handlebars.js for Responsive UI).

Project Make A Difference 6 (Overseas Community Service Project)

Singapore-China

Project Leader

Aug 2012 – Present

- OCSP to rural China involved in road building and a teachers' training programme
- Analysis of overseas host profile and evaluation of areas of need
- Being the proxy for managing stakeholder relations; both local and overseas host partners
- Experience in executive decision making in charting team strategy, policy and planning for engagement
- Management of various departments (Finance, Programmes, Logistics) and facilitating the team members' learning process

StarringSMU (Local Community Service Project)

Singapore

Team Facilitator

Jul 2012 – Aug 2012

- Local CSP involving work with different organizations for the disadvantages over a week
- Led and facilitated the activities and learning for a group of about 20 fellow undergraduates
- Acted as the facilitator in-charge while working with the different CSP liaisons

<u>Proficiency and Skills</u>

Programming/Languages : Java SE, Java EE, PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS, javaScript, XML, Android

Frameworks & APIs : JUnit 4, JQuery, Selenium 2.32, Apache POI 3.9, Sikuli 1.02, Node.js, Meteor.js,

Handlebars.js, D3.JS, Leaflet.js, Struts 2.0.

Databases : SQL Server, MongoDB, PostGreSQL, PostGIS

Design & IDE Tools : Netbeans, Eclipse, Balsamiq, IntelliJ, Websphere Modeler, Visual Studio

Office Tools : MS Excel VBA, MS Visio, MS Project Manager

Others : Adobe Illustrator, InDesign

Professional Qualifications

- ITIL V3 Foundation in Service Management
- Certified Ethical Hacker v8

Currently pursuing these certifications in 2014

- Cisco Certified Network Associate Professional (CCNA)

Reference Projects

Global Disease Analysis (va-kckoh.rhcloud.com/)

SISS Open Portal (siss.sg/openportal.php)

SIS 10th Anniversary Voting Platform (<u>siss.meteor.com/</u>)

Visual analysis of socially stratified disease trends

Undergraduate learning material repository

High volume platform for coding competition